Every town has a story. Tombstone has a legend.
Tombstone is a western, action film directed by George P. Cosmatos.
Legendary marshal Wyatt Earp, now a weary gunfighter, joins his brothers Morgan and Virgil
to pursue their collective fortune in the thriving mining town of Tombstone.
But Earp is forced to don a badge again and get help from his notorious pal Doc Holliday
when a gang of renegade brigands and rustlers begins terrorizing the town.
Wyatt Earp, played by Kurt Russell.
Doc Holliday, played by Val Kilmer.
Johnny Ringo, played by Michael Biehn.
Curly Bill, played by Powers Boothe.
Frank McLaury, played by Robert John Burke.
Josephine, played by Dana Delany.
Tombstone is a 1993 American Western film directed by George P.
Cosmatos, written by Kevin Jarre (who was also the original director, but was replaced early in production), and starring Kurt Russell and Val Kilmer, with
Sam Elliott, Bill Paxton, Powers Boothe, Michael Biehn, Dana Delany and Charlton Heston in supporting roles, and narration by Robert Mitchum.
The film is loosely based on real events that took place in the 1880s in
Southeast Arizona, including the Gunfight at the O.K.
Corral and the Earp Vendetta Ride.
It depicts several Western outlaws and lawmen, such as Wyatt Earp,
William Brocius, Johnny Ringo, and Doc Holliday.
Tombstone was released by Hollywood Pictures in theatrical wide release in the
United States on December 25, 1993, grossing $73.2 million worldwide.
The film was a financial success, and in the Western genre, it ranks
number 25 in the list of highest-grossing films since 1979.
Critical reception was generally positive, with the story,
directing, and acting receiving praise.
Particular praise went towards Val Kilmer's memorable
performance as the hard-drinking Doc Holliday.
The film has become a cult classic since its release.
The film explores themes of right and justice, saloon,
arizona, retirement, historical figure.